<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<undertale>
    <scene route ="neutral">
        <requirements>
            In order to achieve a Nuetral route, the player plays the game as is, but has to do a mixture of sparing enemies and killing enemies. This gives the response of a mixture run where you're not nice by sparing, but not cold hearted by killing too many. Upon beating Omega Flowey, Sans tells the player different text based on which bosses they spare or kill, to show how life is now since the player left the Underground.
        </requirements>
    </scene>
    
    <scene route="pacifist">
        <requirements>
            In order to achieve a True Pacifist route, the player must spare every single enemy they run into, including bosses that seem like they won't let their guard down. After sparing certain bosses, they will have little sidequests for you such as Papyrus inviting you over to Undyne's house to cook spaghetti or helping Alyphs confess her feelings for Undyne. Before going to Asgore, the player is told to go check on Alyphs in her lab in Hotland, allowing the player to explore the True Lab. Beating the True Lab and going to Asgore now will prompt the Pacifist only boss battle with Asreil Dreemur instead.
        </requirements>
    </scene>
    
    <scene route="genocide">
        <requirements>
            In order to achieve a Genocide route, the player must kill every single enemy in a given area, the player will be given a little sound cue when every enemy in the room is defeated. The player will know if they are doing this route correct by almost finding no NPCs around, as the monsters know what you are doing and are hiding from you. The game plays the same until you reach the boss fight with Undyne. Monster Kid sees you are killing monsters and tries fighting you to stop you from going further, upon attacking Monster Kid, Undyne jumps in front and takes the one shot blow, instead of fighting Undyne, you now fight Undyne the Undying, a much stronger and faster version of Undyne. The game changes again when you reach Mettaton, as his true form now is Mettaton NEO, following the same intent as Undyne did, change to a stronger form to stop the player. However, due to coding, Mettaton NEO's defense is in the negatives, allowing for Mettaton NEO to die in one shot no matter what level of violence you are at. The final change is when the player reaches San's judgment before Asgore. Sans sees how high your "level of violence", or LOVE, is and does the same thing, fights the player to stop them. Sans is programmed to be the weakest enemy in the game, but because of repetative attacks that drain health upon getting hit and avoiding attacks the player does, this is one of the hardest on the game. Undyne the Undying, Mettaton NEO, and Sans are all genocide exclusive bosses. Before leaving the Underground, the player is met with Chara, the first fallen human who was friends/siblings with Asreil. It is shown eventually that Chara is the same as Flowey, where both lack emotions to feel love.
        </requirements>
    </scene>
</undertale>
